## JOE D. MALONE

(830) 220-0942 | Joe.D.Malone@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/joe-malone-18126673/ | github.com/JoeDonMalone

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovative full stack developer with 2+ years of demonstrated excellence in designing, building, and implementing UX/UI solutions in a variety of industries. Proven aptitude at familiarization and debugging of complex systems. Effective in a team collaboration setting and efficient in prioritizing workloads for the success of organizational objectives. Seeking a rewarding and challenging career as a Full Stack Developer.

## **SKILLS**

Software Development	Leadership	Soft Skills
Python	Project Management	Analytical Thinking
JavaScript	Client Focused	Detail Oriented
NodeJS	Successful Coaching	Clear Communicator
React	Strategic Planning	Collaboration
MySQL	Conflict Resolution	Problem Solving
jQuery	Team Management	Time Management
MongoDB	Adaptability	Situational Awareness
HTML/CSS	Receptive	

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

2021

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Systems Integrator Control Networks Plus, Cedar Park, TX

Jul 2019 - Present

Working with a small team of integration experts across a spectrum of industries to implement supervisory controls and data acquisition (SCADA) systems. Logistical planning of necessary hardware/software components in complex system designs. Guiding customers in order that they make informed decisions on product purchases and network infrastructure deployments.

- Solely responsible for the design, build, and implementation of a full stack, single source
  project estimating application which eliminates the need for multiple windows programs and
  incorporates a MySQL database of historical records pertaining to all project estimates and
  their revisions. Resulted in a 60% decrease in man-hours associated with the estimating
  process.
- Created tool to parse json objects and assign custom "tooltip" keys for corresponding process variable screen-components. Resulted in the reclamation of 400+ man-hours.
- Implementation of UX/UI design and controls, utilizing the Ignition framework to handle and display pertinent data in a user-friendly and concise manner.
- Reduced the cost of a priority customer ~\$45,000/month on cellular costs for a single facility by interposing the MQTT("Mosquitto") messaging model for client-server data transactions.
- Historized 100% of customers' data model in order that each application transaction promoted process insight and greater value and reliance on company products.

#### JOE D. MALONE

(830) 220-0942 | Joe.D.Malone@gmail.com | <u>linkedin.com/in/joe-malone-18126673/</u> | <u>github.com/JoeDonMalone</u>

# Productivity Specialist/Aftermarket Sales Hexagon Metrology Inc. Irving, TX

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

Responsible for the overall increase of productivity in a customers' manufacturing process. Identified "problem areas" related to customers' shop floor and/or quality control labs. Provided software and hardware solutions, where appropriate, to hit quarterly and yearly sales figures.

- Covered Midwest-South sales territory consisting of TX, LA, AR, OK.
- Exceeded ~\$900,000.00 sales target for 2018 by 18%, despite transitioning into the role during the second half of the sales year.
- Trended towards doubling the sales target of ~\$1,250,000.00 at EOY 2019. Reached 2019 sales quota during first half of sales year, prior to company departure.

#### Field Service Engineer Hexagon Metrology Inc., Irving, Tx

Sep 2013 - Jul 2018

Responsible for the installation, repair, and ISO-10360 certifications of Bridge and Gantry-style Coordinate Measuring Machines (CMM). Focused on delivering outstanding services on behalf of the customer's pursuit of manufacturing and quality excellence.

- Covered Midwest-South service territory consisting of TX, LA, AR, OK, IL
- 491 customer certifications
- 61 successful repairs, 0 failed repairs
- Trained 3 new hires for team of 7
- Mentored over a period of 2.5 years by world Senior Service Engineer, working closely with him to provide priority customer solutions.
- Primary Service Engineer for multiple customers, including Raytheon Co. (Lemmon Ave.), GE
   Oil & Gas, and Bray Controls

#### Avionics Technician U.S. Navy, Norfolk Naval Station, VA

Sep 2008 – Sep 2013

Responsible for the safe flight operations of eight MH-60S helicopter. Retained/utilized multiple cross-division "Collateral Duty Inspector" qualifications necessary to enforce and ensure a structured and by-the-book approach to all aircraft maintenance. Ranking avionics shift supervisor.

- Maintained and updated Cryptology syncs for squadron secret radio communications and IFF transactions
- Managed up to 30 subordinates and trainees in their shift maintenance activities
- 100% mission sortie rating over the duration of 15,000 hours of Operation Enduring Freedom
- Created and administered Command Training Program for over 320 service members

## **EDUCATION**

The Coding Boot Camp at University of Texas at Austin (Expected Graduation) June 2021 Full Stack Developer Certificate

Marble Falls High School

May 2007

Diploma